到了
All right!
太棒了  从家里到医院花了不到七分钟
Yes! From home to the hospital in under seven minutes!
我们办到了
We did it.
对  最艰苦的部分彻底结束了
Yes, the hard part is truly over.
打起精神来
No, but come on,
我们算是开了个好头  对吧
we're off to a great start, aren't we?
我知道可以很快赶过来
I knew I'd get here fast.
但这个速度一定是创下了记录
But this has gotta be some kind of a record!
你们赶到了  嗨
Oh, you made it!  Hi.
你们怎么会比我们先到
How the hell did you beat us here?
我们搭的计程车  你们是走过来的吗
We took a cab. Did you guys walk?
不  我们也是搭计程车  但我做过实验...
No, we took a cab too. But I did test runs...
你们赶到了
Hey, you made it!
好吧  难不成有魔法地道通到这家医院吗
Okay, is there some kind of magic tunnel to this hospital?
罗斯  你留下来聊天
Ross, you stay here and talk.
我要去生孩子了
I'm gonna go have a baby.
好吧  你好  她是瑞秋·格林
Okay. Hi, this is Rachel Greene.
我是罗斯·盖勒  我们在车上打过电话
I'm Ross Geller. We called from the car.
对  我们为你们准备了双人待产室
Right. We have a semiprivate labor room waiting for you, so...
对不起  双人房
Oh, whoa! I'm sorry. Semiprivate?
我们订了单人房
We asked for a private room.
我知道
Yes, I see that here.
不幸地是我们无法保证一定有单人房
Unfortunately, we can't guarantee a private room.
现在单人房都满了
And, currently, they're all unavailable.
你要是早点赶过来就好了
Man, if only you'd gotten here sooner.
抱歉 我们只有双人待产室
I'm sorry. Semiprivate rooms are all we have.
好吧  等我们一下  罗斯
Okay. Just give us a second. Ross?
什么
Yeah?
塞点钱给她
Give her some money.
我觉得他们真的没房间了
I really think they're out of rooms.
才怪  罗斯
They're not, Ross.
他们是为大人物留的
They're just saving them for important people!
好吧  如果我是总统呢
Okay? What if I was the president?
那么我们的麻烦就大了
Well, then, we'd be in a lot of trouble.
你不知道任何国家的地理位置
You don't know where any countries are.
好吧
Okay.
你能再帮我们确认一遍吗
Say, would you mind checking again?
有没有我们可以使用的单人待产室
See if any private rooms may have opened up?
这里是医院
This is a hospital.
好吧  你知道吗  我得说
Okay, you know what? I have to say,
我真的不喜欢你的语气
I don't really care for your tone.
这不是市里唯一一家医院
And this is not the only hospital in this city,
我们完全可以... 天啊
and we have no problem... Oh, gosh!
什么  是阵痛
What? What?  Contraction!
你们想看看双人待产室吗
Would you like to see a semiprivate room?
好吧  看看又何妨
Yeah, it couldn't hurt to look.
《老友记》  第八季  第23集  瑞秋生孩子
Friends S08E23 The One Where Rachel Has A Baby
你的子宫颈只开了两公分
Well, you're only two centimeters dilated,
得等开到十公分才行
and we need to get to 10.
那得等上一段时间  好吧
It'll be a while.  Oh, okay.
我一小时后再回来帮你检查  谢谢
I'll be back in an hour to check you again. Thank you.
看来这段时间我们有的闲了
I guess we have some time to kill.
没错
Yeah, guess so.
你看
Oh, check these out.
我以前从没这么玩过
Never done this before.
对  看起来棒极了
Yeah, well, it looks great.
谢谢  我想我们准备好...
Thank you very much. I think we're ready to...
嗨  我是罗斯
Hi, I'm Ross.
抱歉毁了你们的大好日子
I'm here to ruin this magical day for you.
一点都不会  没关系的
Oh, no, not at all. It's okay.
马克·何格  她是我太太茱莉
Marc Horger. This is my wife, Julie.
嗨  茱莉  她是瑞秋
Hi, Julie. This is Rachel.
嗨  瑞秋
Oh, hi, Rachel.
这是你的第一胎  对
Is this your first?  Yeah, it is.
小吉米是我们的第三胎
Well, little Jamie here is our third.
如果你们有问题
So if you have any questions,
或需要帮忙  叫我们一声就好
or you need anything at all, just holler.
那真是太棒了  对
That's so sweet.  Yeah.
我之前把帘子拉开了  我来给你们留点隐私
I opened this earlier but let me give you guys some privacy.
没关系  我们同舟共济
Nonsense. We're all in this together.
我们愿意跟你们分享待产的每一刻
We are gonna share every moment of this with you.
我想我们会相处得非常愉快  对
And I think we're gonna have some fun.  Yeah.
好吧  笑一个
Oh, okay, I guess.  Hey, smile!
我不知道...  我真的不要...
I don't know if...  I really don't want any...
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
罗斯  我又开始阵痛了
Oh, Ross! Here comes another contraction.
好吧  深呼吸
Okay, just breathe.
老公  我也开始阵痛了
Oh, honey, I think I'm having one too!
来吧  不
Here you go!  Oh, no!
天啊
Oh, my God!
你看
Hey, look at this.
三个小时过去了还是没生
Oh, wow. Three hours and still no baby.
生产的奇迹让人很想打磕睡
The miracle of birth sure is a snoozefest.
你要看点好玩的事吗
Hey, you wanna see something?
当然  什么
Sure. What?
这一定会很有意思
This is gonna be fun.
看我怎么吓钱德勒
Watch me freak out Chandler.
老公  什么事
Honey?  Yeah?
听着  我一直在想
Listen, I've been doing some thinking...
我不知道是因为我们身处医院
...and I don't know whether it's because we're here...
还是瑞秋要生孩子了
...or Rachel's giving birth...
但我觉得我们应该开始造小孩了
...but I think we should try to have a baby.
好吧
Okay.
你说什么
What's that now?
好吧  我也一直在想这件事
Okay. I've been thinking about it too,
我觉得我们准备好了
and I think we're ready.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你觉得我们现在就准备好要怀孕了
You think we're ready to have a baby now?
这确实很好玩
This is fun.
你们准备要怀孕了
You're ready to have a baby?
我的小男孩长大了
My boy's all grown up!
你说你也准备好了
You said you were ready too.
对  我只是想跟你开玩笑
Yeah, but I was just screwing with you
逼你用高八度的怪声音说话
to try to get your voice all high and weird...
就像我现在一样
...like mine is now!
对  但你不是一直都想要生孩子吗
Yes, but haven't you wanted a kid, like, forever?
好吧  滚开  先生
Okay, then, back off, mister!
我确实准备好生孩子了
Because I am ready to have a baby.
我只是希望乔伊是孩子他爸
I just want Joey to be the father.
什么  你疯了吗
What? Are you crazy?
就是那样  那就是我的目的
That's it, right there! That's all I wanted!
实在抱歉
I am so sorry.
医生坚持要拉上帘子做检查
The doctor insisted on closing the curtain for the exam.
那非常... 真的没关系
Oh, that's very... Really, very, very okay.
茱莉的子宫颈开了七公分
Julie's cervix is dilated seven centimeters.
大约是四指宽
That's about four fingers!
医生让我自己摸摸看
Doctor let me feel it myself.
你摸过瑞秋的子宫颈吗  罗斯
Have you felt Rachel's cervix, Ross?
没有  我们不会那么做  我们不会那么做
No, we're not gonna do that.  We won't be doing that.
如果你愿意的话  你可以摸摸瑞秋的
Well, if you like, you could feel Rachel's,
再摸摸我的做比较
then feel mine to compare.
我打扰了你们吗
Am I interrupting?
太棒了  谢谢  待会见
Yes! Thank you! Later.
不  你不能丢下我跟他们独处  对不起
No, you can't leave me alone with these people. Oh, I'm sorry.
不  罗斯  我的孩子没有父亲
No, Ross? Ross? Ross? My child has no father!
很高兴你能过来  可能还要再等一阵
I'm so glad you're here, but it's gonna be a while.
你该先打电话来
I wish you'd called first.
没关系  我待会再跟你爸来一趟
That's all right. I'm coming back later with your father.
在孩子出生前  我得跟你谈一谈
I acturally needed to talk to you before the birth.
好吧  什么事
Okay. What's up?
我有样东西要给你
I brought something that I want to give you.
当然前提是你需要的话
Assuming, of course, that you want it.
妈  你要我娶你吗
Ma, you're asking me to marry you?
这是你外婆的订婚戒指
This is your grandmother's engagement ring.
我要你把它送给瑞秋
I want you to give it to Rachel.
妈  不  别这样
Mom, no. Come on.
谢谢你  听我说...
Thank you.  Just hear me out...
不要  我们谈过了
No! Okay? We've been through this.
我们不会因为她怀孕了就去结婚  好吗
We're not gonna get married just because she's pregnant. Okay?
说真的  罗斯
Honestly, Ross,
她不是你在酒吧泡到就上的女孩
this isn't just some girl you picked up in a bar and humped.
罗斯  孩子应该要有个完整的家庭
Ross, a child should have a family.
你知道吗  我现在无法思考此事  抱歉
You know what? I can't deal with this right now. I'm sorry.
考虑一下吧
Just think about it.
如果你不收  我会再跟你谈上女孩的事
If you don't, I'll talk more about humping.
给我吧
Give me.
嗨  亲爱的  谢谢你赶过来
Hi, dear.  Hi. Thank you so much for coming.
罗斯  快进来
Ross, get in here!
她把我拖出待产室
She dragged me out of the labor room
问我为什么不跟瑞秋结婚
to ask me why I'm not with Rachel.
对
Yeah.
你为什么不跟瑞秋结婚
Why aren't you with Rachel?
你在开玩笑吗
You're kidding, right?
我们不会因为孩子的关系就去办结婚
Look, we're not gonna be together just because we're having this baby.
但你们俩看着很般配
But it just seems that you two belong together.
别说了  现在我没法想这件事
Okay, stop it. I can't deal with this right now.
我得去等孩子出生
I have to go have a baby.
对  孩子他妈是谁来着
Right. And with who again?
他简直疯了 他为什么不想跟瑞秋结婚
He's crazy. Why doesn't he wanna be with Rachel?
就是啊
I know.
说真的  她是个完美的姑娘
Seriously, she's like the perfect woman.
我知道她拒绝了我...
I mean, I know she turned me down...
如果她没有拒绝  她想跟我在一起
...but if she hadrt and she wanted to be with me...
我会抱着她...
...I would take her in my arms and...
我有一阵子没有这样吓你们了吧
I haven't bummed you guys out like this in a while, have I ?
那是谁  新来的
Who's that?  New people.
恶心夫妇怎么了
What happened to the Disgustingtons?
他们去生孩子了
They're having their baby.
这不公平  罗斯  是我先来的
It's not fair, Ross. I got here first!
你离开不久  他们就将她推进产房了
Right after you left, they wheeled her off into delivery.
但她走之前  她的产道如鲜花怒放
Oh, but not before she gave me a nice, juicy shot of little Jamie
画面十分生动
just crowning away.
抱歉
Wow. Sorry.
新来的人怎么样
So how are the new people?
他们给对方起的昵称都很奇怪
Well, they have some unusual pet names for each other.
其中有"恶婆娘"和"臭混蛋"
Including "Evil Bitch" and "Sick Bastard."
天啊  阵痛
Oh, gosh, a contraction.
是吗  好了  深呼吸
Yeah? Okay, okay. Just breathe.
你在看她吗  不
Are you looking at her?  No!
别看她  你个臭混蛋
Don't you look at her, you sick bastard!
我发誓  没有在看她
Honey, I swear I wasn't looking at her!
她在生小孩
She's in labor.
你喜欢吗  你个狗娘养的
You like that, you sick son of a bitch?
我还是把...
I'm just gonna...
看吧  都是你偷看的关系  变态死胖子
See? It's because you were looking, you fat pervert.
不  我相信没有人在偷看
No, no. I'm sure no one was looking.
我们只是需要一点隐私
Just want some privacy.
你想念你的女朋友吗
You miss your girlfriend?
别管他们
Just ignore them.
你没事吧  没事
You okay?  Yeah.
罗斯  怎么了
Ross.  What?
他在盯着我看
He's looking at me.
你还想活着看到自己的孩子出生吗
You wanna live to see your baby?
你竟敢这么跟我老公说话  你个臭混蛋
Don't you talk to my husband like that, you stupid bastard!
天啊  如果你那么想要孩子  去偷一个吧
Oh, good God! If you want a baby so bad, just go steal it!
你是怎么了
What is going on with you.
你什么时候这么喜欢孩子了
Since when are you so crazy about babies?
我不是喜欢孩子  我是喜欢和你在一起
I'm not crazy about babies. I'm crazy about us.
什么
What?
我们总是说以后要生孩子
We've always talked about having babies someday,
我没说非得是现在
I'm not saying it has to be right now,
但我觉得我们现在能应付得来
...but I'm starting to think that we can handle it.
我们准备好了
We're good.
我们真的准备好了
We're really good.
我们准备齐全了
We are pretty good.
但你没准备好前我是不会行动的
But nothing has to happen until you're ready.
也许我现在就准备好了
Well, maybe I'm ready now.
虽说稍微有点吓人  但感觉对了
I mean, it's a little scary, but maybe it's right.
什么感觉对了
What? It's not right!
我们还没有准备好要生孩子
We're not ready to have a kid now!
什么
What?
我在开玩笑  这一定会很好玩
I'm kidding. This is gonna be fun.
我们要试试看吗  我们现在就要试吗
So we're gonna try? I mean, we're trying?
我们要试着怀孕
We're trying to get pregnant.
我不想在宝宝面前干这种勾当
I'm not comfortable doing this in front of the babies.
你想什么时候开始试
So when do you want to start trying?
好吧  等一下
All right, hold on a sec.
你在算生理周期  对
Period math?  Yeah.
我们可以从现在开始
Well, we could start trying now.
在这里吗  不是
Right here?  No, not here.
这里也可以啊
Maybe here.
这里太适合了  我们有大把时间要消磨
It's perfect. We got a lot of time to kill,
而且医院里到处都是床
and we're in a building that's full of beds!
还很干净
And it's so clean!
快点  你这台蠢机器  来嘛
Come on, you stupid machine! Come on!
把你的钱吃掉了吗
It ate your money?
没有
No.
那么楼下见  好吧
I'll see you downstairs then.  All right.
我拿到了
Hey, I got one! I got one!
上还是下  下楼  谢谢
Oh, up or down?  Oh. Down, please.
我讨厌抢男人的风头  但可以由我来吗
I hate to be a ballbuster, but can I just do it?
麻烦你帮我按上  没问题
Could you press up too?  Sure.
我真的很遗憾  我也曾摔断过腿
I feel bad for you. I broke my leg once too.
是吗  你怎么会摔断腿
Yeah? How'd yours happen?
说来话长  有点丢脸
Well, it's a long story, it's kind of embarrassing.
其实是性爱手册排版上出了点小错误
Let's just say there was a typographical error with a sex manual.
你呢  车祸
How about you?  Car accident.
有个白痴在打手机  没注意看路
Let me guess. Some idiot on a cell phone wasn't paying attention?
对  就是我
Yeah. Me.
我的电梯来了
Oh, hey, that's me.
我猜你是来探病的  没错
Hey, I take it you're just visiting someone.  Yeah.
如果你有时间  想探望其他人...
Well, if you have some time and you wanna visit someone else...
对  我很乐意
Yeah, I would like that.
等一下  不要啊
Wait! What? No!
电梯等等
Elevator! No!
你得按按钮才行
You gotta press the button.
护士说他们要送另一位女人过来
The nurse said they're bringing in another woman.
她已经怀孕了吗
Oh. Is she pregnant yet?
她根本不需要怀孕
She doesn't need to be.
她还是能赶在我之前把孩子生下来
She'll still have the baby before I do.
罗斯  我又阵痛了  好吧
Oh, Ross! Another contraction.  Oh, okay. Here, here.
没错
That's it.
听起来好像很痛  没错
Oh, that sounded like a bad one.  Yeah, it was.
我的阵痛没有那么厉害  又来了
Mine haven't been so bad. Oh, here comes one now.
真的好痛
Oh, that was a big one.
打扰一下  你能帮我个忙吗
Excuse me, could you help me with something?
我在找一位一条腿骨折的病人
The patient I'm looking for has a broken leg.
他坐着轮椅  31到35岁  非常迷人
He's in a wheelchair. He's early to mid30s, very attractive.
我知道你在说谁
I know who you're talking about.
太棒了  他住几号病房
Great! What room number is he in?
小姐  对不起
Ma'am, I'm sorry.
只有医院人员能查看资料
That information is restricted to hospital staff.
她跟我是一起的  德雷克·拉莫瑞医生
She's with me. Dr. Drake Ramoray.
哪个德雷克医生
Dr. Drake who?
拉莫瑞  那是葡萄牙姓氏
Ramoray. It's Portuguese.
我们需要他的资料  我是医生
We need that information. I'm a doctor.
这间医院的医生
A doctor at this hospital?
该死  我们正在浪费宝贵的时间
Damn it, we're losing precious time.
你希望头上沾上这个男人的血...
You want this man's blood on your head...?
是手  手上
Hands.  Hands!
你必须告诉我
It is absolutely essential that you tell me
我助手描述的病人住几号病房
what room the man my assistant described is staying in.
他是我的病人  我为他治疗多年了
He's a patient of mine. I've treated him for years.
他住816号病房  816  谢谢
He's in room 816.  816. Thank you.
他叫什么名字  不要
And what is his name?  No.
我们找到地方了  好吧
I think we found a place.  Okay.
等一下  你想增加点气氛吗
Wait. Wanna set the mood a little?
好  把灯调暗  好吧
Okay. We'll dim the lights.  Okay.
或是通通关掉
Or turn them out altogether.
没有精油蜡烛  好吧  来  喷一喷
No scented candles. Okay, here. There we go.
好吧  帮我消了毒（不孕）  但没关系
Okay, okay. Making me sterile, but okay.
对不起  等一下  我们有安全套吗
Okay. I'm sorry. Oh, wait. Do we have a condom?
对了
Oh, right!
好  37摄氏度  你没有大碍
Yes, 98.6. You're gonna be fine.
就是这里
This is it!
就是他  太棒了  去找他吧
That's him!  Great. Go get him!
等一下  你可以先进去
Wait a second. Or maybe you could go in first.
他真的不是我的菜
He's not really my type.
不是以你的身份  而是拉莫瑞医生
Not you. Dr. Drake Ramoray.
你可以问他问题  看看他是个什么样的人
You could ask him questions and see what he's like.
大家对医生什么都肯说
People tell doctors everything.
你说他是个好男人
But you said he was this great guy.
我认识的男人一开始看上去都很好
Lately all the guys I meet seem nice at first,
最后都成了大混蛋
then turn out to be the biggest jerks.
你的确吸引了一些烂男人  对  我知道
You do attract some stinkers.  Yeah, I know.
朗医生 我已经等了17个小时
Dr. Long, I've been at this for 17 hours.
三个女人进进出出  生下了孩子
Three women have come and gone with their babies.
你得给我点好消息
You gotta give me good news.
我张开了几公分  八  九
How many centimeters am I dilated? Eight? Nine?
三  只有三公分
Three.  Just three?
我都张开三公分了
I'm dilated three!
虽说慢了点  但还是有进展的
We are moving along, just slowly.
放心  你做得很好
Don't worry, you're doing great.
我马上回来  谢谢
I'll be back soon.  Thank you.
你知道吗  我不想等了
You know what? I'm not waiting.
我要把孩子生出来
I'm gonna push this baby out.
我现在就要生  三公分
I'm doing it. Three centimeters.
大概有这么宽吧
That's gotta be like this, right?
事实上是这么宽
Actually, it's more like this.
愚蠢的公制系统
Oh, stupid metric system.
天啊  我们得直接把你推进产房了
Oh, my. We're gonna need to take you straight to the delivery room.
行行好吧
Oh, for the love of God!
我是德雷克·拉莫瑞医生
I'm Dr. Drake Ramoray.
我得问你几个例行的问题
I have a few routine questions I need to ask you.
真的吗  一直是威尔斯医生帮我治疗
Really? I've been dealing with Dr. Wells.
我知道  我是神经科医生
I know. I'm a neurologist.
为了预防万一...
Just to be on the safe side...
威尔斯医生需要更多相关资料
...Dr. Wells wanted a more comprehensive overview over your status.
所以他请我过来
So he sent me.
威尔斯医生是女的
Dr. Wells is a woman!
这是其中一项测试  反应不错
That was a test. Good response.
好吧  全名  克利夫·伯奈特
All right. Full name?  Clifford Burnett.
生日  1968年11月16日
Date of birth?  November 16, 1968.
年龄
Age?
你不会根据生日自己算吗
Can't you figure that out based on my date of birth?
我是医生  又不是数学家
I'm a doctor, not a mathematician.
33岁  好吧
I'm 33.  Okay.
已婚吗  没有
And are you married?  No.
真的吗  33岁还是单身
Oh, really? So 33 and single?
你害怕许下承诺吗
Would you say you have commitment issues?
所有的问题都涉及隐私吗
Are all the questions this personal?
对
Yes.
如果一定要回答的话  我是鳏夫
Well, if you must know, I'm a widower.
太不幸了  我真的很遗憾  没事
Oh, that's terrible. I'm really sorry.  Yeah.
你跟女人上床之后  会再也不联系她吗
Do you sleep with women and never call them again?
不会  太棒了
No.  Excellent. Excellent.
最后一题  你有奇怪的性癖好吗
And finally, are you into any weird stuff, you know, sexually?
没有  答错了
No!  Wrong answer.
还有呢  他33岁
What else? What else?  He's 33.
是个鳏夫
A widower.
他似乎是个靠谱的男人
He seemed like a stand up guy.
他没有奇怪的性癖好
And he's not into anything weird sexually.
菲比要出马了
Enter Pheebs!
这个房间是空的
This room's available.
好吧  等一下  听我说
Okay! Wait, you listen to me! You listen to me!
我的子宫颈才张开三公分
Since I have been waiting, four women, that's four,
就已经有四个女人
one higher than the number of centimeters I'm dilated...
被推进来  又被推出去  生下了孩子
...have come and gone with their babies.
下一个是我  轮到我了  那才公平
I'm next. It's my turn. It's only fair.
如果你再推个女人进来  她又比我先生
If you bring in one more woman who has her baby before me,
我就要告你了
I'm going to sue you.
不告这家医院  我要告你
Not this hospital. I'm gonna sue you.
我先生是律师
My husband is a lawyer.
瑞秋  你继续处理那个案子  亲爱的
Rach?  You get back on that case, honey!
我想下一位产妇不会太快生
I don't think the next patient is very far along.
好吧  那把她推进来吧
Okay. Well, then bring her in.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe this!
但这却是真的
And yet, somehow, it's true.
这简直太棒了
I mean, this is so great.
我们可以指腹为婚
We're gonna be baby buddies!
把你的双腿并拢  别让宝宝听见
Squeeze your legs together and cover the baby's ears.
嗨  老婆  嗨  老公
Hi, sweetie!  Hi, sweetheart.
他是我丈夫希德   你们应该没见过他
This is my husband, Sid. I don't think you've met him.
罗斯  瑞秋  他是希德
Ross, Rachel, this is Sid.
一年前我在皮肤科诊所认识他
I nabbed him a year ago at the dermatologist's office.
还好我长了成人型青春痘
Thank God for adult acne!
我还是不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
我是全世界最幸运的人
I'm the luckiest guy in the world.
真的吗
Really?
他说什么
What'd he say?
你得大声一点  他几乎完全失去听力了
You have to speak very loudly, he's almost completely deaf.
没错  我就说嘛
Oh, there you go.  Of course he is.
恭喜你们
So, congratulations, you two.
我都不知道你们结婚了
I didn't even know you got married.
我们没结婚  什么
Oh, we didn't.  What?
我们只是要一起生下这个孩子  就是那样
We're just having this baby together, but that's all, you know.
为什么
Why?
我们还没到那个程度  知道吗
We're just not in that place, you know?
但我们很期待宝宝的出生
But we're very excited about this.
那我就没话说了（让我闭嘴）
Oh. Well, then shut me up.
告诉我该怎么办
Just tell me how.
我又开始阵痛了
Oh, I feel another one coming.